

# Mohammadreza Zakeri

#### Research Interests

My research is focused primarily on models beyond the Standard Model (SM), designed for the purpose of explaining the nature of Dark Matter (DM) and the origin of neutrino mass. I work on gauge extensions of the SM, flavor physics, radiative processes, direct and indirect signatures of DM in experiments. My work also involves testing various models using the data from particle colliders such as the LHC. I also analyze the results from cosmic ray detectors like DAMPE, and AMS-02 to constrain new models.

# Employment

2017-2020 Postdoc at Institute of Theoretical Physics (ITP), Chinese Academy of Sciences (CAS).
Beijing, P. R. China

2012-2017 Teaching Assistant at UC Riverside.

California, USA

## Education

2012-2017 University of California, Riverside, Riverside, California

Doctor of Philosophy (2017), Master of Science (2013)

Advisor: Ernest Ma

PhD Thesis: "Extensions of the Standard Model with Dark Matter in Some Explicit Examples"

PhD Defense Date: June 21st 2017 (Received on September 16th 2017)

2008-2012 **Sharif University of Technology**, Tehran, Iran.

Bachelor of Science in Physics

2001-2008 Rouzbeh Institute, Tehran, Iran.

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

#### Awards & Honors

- 2019 CAS President's International Fellowship Initiative (PIFI) from the Chinese Academy of Sciences
- 2017 Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award from the Department of Physics & Astronomy at UCR
- 2016 Three GSA Conference Travel Grant Awards from UC Riverside
- 2012 Dean's Distinguished Fellowship from Graduate Division of UC Riverside
- 2011 Ranked 4<sup>th</sup> in the nationwide M.Sc. entrance exam in physics in Iran

#### Publications

- 1. Exotic Lepton-Flavor Violating Higgs Decays, J. A. Evans, P. Tanedo, M. Zakeri, JHEP 01 (2020) 028, [arXiv:1910.07533].
- 2. Non-Abelian Vector Boson as FIMP Dark Matter, B. Barman, S. Bhattacharya, M. Zakeri, JCAP 02 (2020) 029, [arXiv:1905.07236].

- 3. Multipartite Dark Matter in  $SU(2)_N$  Extension of Standard Model and Signatures at the LHC, B. Barman, S. Bhattacharya, M. Zakeri, JCAP 09 (2018) 023, [arXiv:1806.01129].
- 4. A Minimal Model For Two-Component FIMP Dark Matter: A Basic Search, S. P. Zakeri, S. M. MoosaviNejad, S. Y. Ayazi, M. Zakeri, Chin. Phys. C42 (2018) no.7, 073101, [arXiv:1801.09115].
- 5. Alternative [SU(3)]<sup>4</sup> Model of Leptonic Color and Dark Matter, C. Kownacki, E. Ma, N. Pollard, O. Popov, M. Zakeri, Nucl. Phys. B928 (2018) 520-534, [arXiv:1801.01379].
- 6. Dark Revelations of the [SU(3)]<sup>3</sup> and [SU(3)]<sup>4</sup> Gauge Extensions of the Standard Model, *C. Kownacki, E. Ma, N. Pollard, O. Popov, M. Zakeri*, Phys. Lett. B777 (2018) 121-124, [arXiv:1710.00762].
- 7. Dark Gauge U(1) Symmetry for an Alternative Left-Right Model, C. Kownacki, E. Ma, N. Pollard, O. Popov, M. Zakeri, Eur. Phys. J. C78 (2018) no.2, 148, [arXiv:1706.06501].
- 8. Quartified Leptonic Color, Bound States, and Future Electron-Positron Collider, C. Kownacki, E. Ma, N. Pollard, O. Popov, M. Zakeri, Phys. Lett. B769 (2017) 267-271, [arXiv:1701.07043].
- 9. **Generalized Gauge U(1) Family Symmetry for Quarks and Leptons**, *C. Kownacki, E. Ma, N. Pollard, M. Zakeri*, Phys. Lett. B766 (2017) 149-152, [arXiv:1611.05017].
- 10. Gauge B-L Model of Radiative Neutrino Mass with Multipartite Dark Matter, E. Ma, N. Pollard, O. Popov, M. Zakeri, Mod. Phys. Lett. A31 (2016) no. 27, 1650163, [arXiv:1605.00991].
- 11. Phenomenology of the Utilitarian Supersymmetric Standard Model, S. Fraser, C. Kownacki, E. Ma, N. Pollard, O. Popov, M. Zakeri, Nucl. Phys. B 909, 644 (2016), [arXiv:1603.04778].
- 12. **Verifiable Associated Processes from Radiative Lepton Masses with Dark Matter**, *S. Fraser, E. Ma, M. Zakeri*, Phys. Rev. D 93, 115019 (2016), [arXiv:1511.07458].
- 13. **Gauge B–L Model with Residual**  $Z_3$  **Symmetry**, E.  $M_3$ , N. Pollard, R. Srivastava, M. Zakeri, Phys. Lett. B750 (2015) 135-138, [arXiv:1507.03943].
- 14.  $SU(2)_N$  Model of Vector Dark Matter with a Leptonic Connection, S. Fraser, E. Ma, M. Zakeri, Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 30, 1550018 (2015), [arXiv:1409.1162].

#### Talks & Posters

- Exotic Lepton-Flavor Violating Higgs Decays, Conference Talk: New physics beyond the Standard Model (PICTP program).
   Beijing, China, Oct 2019
- 2. Dark Gauge U(1) and the DAMPE Signal, Poster: KEK Theory Meeting 2018(KEK-PH2018).

Tsukuba, Japan, Feb 2018

- 3. **Leptonic Color, and the Future Electron-Positron Collider**, *Journal Club Talk: Institute of Theoretical Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences*.

  Beijing, China, Nov 2017
- 4. **Gauge B–L Model with Residual**  $Z_3$  **Symmetry**, *Invited Talk: BLV 2017*. Cleveland, OH, USA, May 2017
- Quartified Leptonic Color, Bound States, and Future Electron-Positron Collider, Journal Club Talk: UC, Riverside.
   Riverside, CA, USA, May 2017
- 6. **Leptonic Color, and the Future Electron-Positron Collider**, *Invited Talk: Institute of Modern Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences*.

  Lanzhou, China, Dec 2016

- Asymmetric Reheating After Inflation, Poster: COSMO-16.
   Ann Arbor, MI, USA, Aug 2016
- 8. Radiative Lepton Masses, Conference Talk: Phenomenology 2016 Symposium. Pittsburgh, PA, USA, May 2016

## Conferences & Schools

- 1. PICTP program: New physics beyond the Standard Model, Beijing, China, Oct 2019
- 2. KEK Theory Meeting 2018(KEK-PH2018), Tsukuba, Japan, Feb 2018
- 3. Winter School on Gravitational-Wave Data Analysis, Beijing, China, Dec 2017
- 4. International Workshop on Baryon & Lepton Number Violation 2017, Cleveland, OH, USA, May 2017
- 5. SOCAL BSM 2017, Riverside, CA, USA, Apr 2017
- 6. COSMO-16, Ann Arbor, MI, USA, Aug 2016
- 7. TASI Summer School, Boulder, CO, USA, June-July 2016
- 8. Phenomenology 2016 Symposium, Pittsburgh, PA, USA, May 2016

# Teaching Experiences

	University	of	California	Riverside	Riverside.	California
--	------------	----	------------	-----------	------------	------------

- Summer 2017 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040B: General Physics Laboratory
  - Spring 2017 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040B: General Physics
  - Winter 2017 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 02LB: General Physics Laboratory
    - Fall 2016 Course Grader, PHYS 221A: Quantum Mechanics
      Teaching Assistant, PHYS 156A: Quantum Mechanics
- Summer 2016 Instructor, Physics GRE Preparation Course
  - Spring 2016 Course Grader, PHYS 221C: Quantum Mechanics

Course Grader, PHYS 212B: Thermodynamics And Statistical Mechanics

- Winter 2016 Course Grader, PHYS 221B: Quantum Mechanics

  Teaching Assistant, PHYS 156B: Quantum Mechanics
  - Fall 2015 Course Grader, PHYS 221A: Quantum Mechanics

    Teaching Assistant, PHYS 156A: Quantum Mechanics
- Summer 2015 Instructor, Physics GRE Preparation
  - Spring 2015 Course Grader, PHYS 221C: Quantum Mechanics Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040B: General Physics
  - Winter 2015 Course Grader, PHYS 221B: Quantum Mechanics

    Teaching Assistant, PHYS 156B: Quantum Mechanics
    - Fall 2014 Course Grader, PHYS 221A: Quantum Mechanics

      Teaching Assistant, PHYS 156A: Quantum Mechanics
- Summer 2014 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040C: General Physics
  - Spring 2014 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040C: General Physics
  - Winter 2014 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 02LB: General Physics Laboratory
    - Fall 2013 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040C: General Physics Laboratory
- Summer 2013 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040C: General Physics Laboratory
  - Spring 2013 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 040C: General Physics Laboratory
  - Winter 2013 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 02LB: General Physics Laboratory

Fall 2012 Teaching Assistant, PHYS 02LA: General Physics Laboratory

Rouzbeh Institute, Tehran, Iran

Summer 2010 Teacher, 3DS MAX Software

Fall 2010 Teacher, Adobe After Effect Software

## Computer Skills

**Python** Have experience with NumPy, SciPy, matplotlib, pandas, sklearn, quandl, multiprocessing, subprocess, math, random, re, cv2, shutil, time, os, sys, logging, gzip, tarfile, Tkinter, Pygame and the standard library.

**C++** Have experience with omp, random, algorithm, cmath, array, string, ctime, chrono, fstream, vector, iostream libraries.

HEP MadGraph, Pythia, Root, FastJet, FeynRules, FeynCalc, FeynArts, CalcHEP, SARAH

Others Linux, LATEX, Mathematica, MATLAB, Inkscape

GitHub github.com/ZAKI1905

# Languages

Farsi Native proficiency in writing, reading, listening and speaking

**English** Bilingual proficiency in writing, reading, listening and speaking

Mandarin Limited working proficiency in reading, listening, speaking, writing

## Personal Details

Place of Birth Tehran, Iran

Date of Birth July 23rd 1990

Nationality Iranian

Website zaki.netlify.com

#### References

Adviser **Zhou, Yu-Feng**, *Email:* yfzhou@itp.ac.cn, *Professor at Institute of Theoretical Physics (ITP), Beijing, China.* 

PhD Adviser **Ernest Ma**, *Email:* ma@phyun8.ucr.edu, *Professor Emeritus at University of California, Riverside, USA.* 

- Flip Tanedo, Email: flip.tanedo@ucr.edu, Assistant Prof. at University of California, Riverside, USA.
- Hai-Bo Yu, Email: hai-bo.yu@ucr.edu, Assistant Prof. at University of California, Riverside, USA.